In the previous video, you saw
a few examples of how vectorization
从上节视频中，你知道了怎样矢量化
by using built-in functions and
by avoiding explicit for
通过numpy内置函数以及避开循环loop方式
loops allows you to speed
up your code significantly.
有效的提高代码速度
Let's take a look at a few more examples.
下面看看另外的一些例子
The rule of thumb to keep in mind is when
you're programming your neural networks or
经验提醒我，当我们在写神经网络程序时
when you're programming logistic
regression, whenever possible,
或者在写逻辑(logistic)回归，或者其他神经网络模型时
avoid explicit for loops.
应该避免写循环(loop)语句
And it's not always possible
to never use a for loop.
虽然有时写循环(loop)是不可避免的
But when you can use a built-in function,
or find some other way to compute
但是我们可以使用比如numpy内置函数去计算
whatever you need, it'll often go faster
than if you had an explicit for loop.
当你这样使用后，程序效率总是快于循环(loop)
Let's look at another example.
让我们看另外一个例子
If ever you want to compute a vector
u as the product of a matrix A and
如果你想计算向量u = 矩阵A乘以v (u=Av)
another vector v, then the definition of
这时矩阵乘法定义为
a matrix multiplier is
that your ui = sum over i
Ui = sum_i sum_j A(ij) V(j)
sum over j Aij VJ,
that's how you define UI.
（如图所示）这取决于你怎么定义U(i)值
And so the non vectorization
implementation of this
同样使用非矢量化实现
would be to set U = np.zeros( n, 1), and
U 等于 np.zeros(n,1) 并且
then for i and so on,
for j and so on, right.
通过两层循环 for i :  for j:
And then u[i] += A[i][j] * v[j].
得到 u[i] += A[i][j] * v[j].
So now this has two for
loops looping over both i and j.
现在就有了i和j的两层循环
So that's a non vectorization.
这就是非矢量化
The vectorized implementation
would say u = np.A, v.
矢量化方式就可以用 u = np.dot(A,v)
And the implementation on
the right the vectorized
右边这种矢量化实现方式
version now eliminates two different for
loops and it's going to be way faster.
消除了两层循环使得代码运行速度更快
Let's go through one more example.
下面通过另一个例子
Let's say you already have a vector
v in memory and you want to
如果你已经有一个向量 v
apply the exponential operation on
every element of say it is vector v.
并且想要对向量v的每个元素做指数操作
So you compute u = vector,
that's e to v1, e to the v2,
得到向量u 等于 e的v1 ， e的v2
and so on down to e to the Vn.
一直到e的vn 次方
So this would be a non-vectorized
implementation, which is that first,
这里是非向量化的实现方式
you initialize u to a vector of zeroes.
首先你初始化了向量u = np.zeros(n,1)
And then you have a for loop that
computes the elements one at a time.
并且通过循环依次计算每个元素
But it turns out that Python NumPy have
many built in functions that allow you to
但事实证明可以通过python的numpy内置函数
compute these vectors with just
a single call to a single function.
帮助你计算这样的单个函数
So what I would do to implement
this is import NumPy as np.
所以我会引入(import) numpy 取别名为(as) np
And then what you just call
u equals np.e to the (v).
执行 u = np.exp(v) 命令
And so notice that whereas previously
you had a explicit for loop,
注意到  在之前有循环的代码中
with just one line of code here, does V
as an input vector use an output vector?
这里仅用了一行代码， 向量v作为输入， u作为输出
You've got to rail up the explicit for
loop, and the implementation on the right
你已经知道为什么需要循环，并且通过右边代码实现
will be much faster than the one
medium explicit for loop.
效率会明显的快于循环方式
In fact, the NumPy library has many
of the vector value functions.
事实上，numpy库有很多向量函数
So np.log of v will compute
the element wise log,
比如np.log 是计算对数函数(log)
np.abs computes the absolute value,
np.abs是计算数据的绝对值
np.maximum computes
the element y's maximum.
np.maximum计算元素y中的最大值
So you take the max of
every element of v with 0.
你也可以np.maximum(v,0)
v**2 just takes the element y's
square of each element of v.
v**2代表获得元素y每个值得平方
1/v takes the element y's inverse and so on.
1/v 获取元素y的逆 等等
So whenever you are tempted to write the
for loop, take a look and see if there's
所以当你想写循环时候
a way to call a NumPy built in function
to do it without that for loop.
检查numpy是否存在类似的内置函数 从而避免使用循环(loop)方式
So, let's take all of these learnings and
那么 将刚才所学到的内容
apply it to our logistic regression
gradient descent implementation and
运用在逻辑回归的梯度下降上
see if we can at least get rid of
one of the two folders that we had.
看看我们是否能简化两个计算过程中的某一步
So here's our code for computing
the derivatives for logistic regression.
这是我们逻辑回归的求导代码
And we had two for loops.
有两层循环
One was this one up here.
这是一个循环
And the second one was this one, right?
这儿是第二个循环
So in our example we had n or nx = 2.
在这例子我们有n 或者nx =2 特征值
But if you had more features than just
two features then you need to have a for
如果你有超过两个特征时
loop over dw1, dw2, dw3, and so on.
需要循环dw1 dw2 dw3 等等
So it's as if there's actually a for
j = 1, 2 and x.
所以j的实际值是1 ，2 和 x
dwj, dwj your guest updated, right.
dwj就是你想要更新的值
So we'd like to eliminate this second
volume, that's what we'll do on this line.
所以我们想要消除第二循环，在这一行
So the way we'll do so is that instead
of explicitly initializing dw1,
这样我们就不用初始化dw1
dw2 and so on to 0s,
we're going to get rid of this.
dw2 都等于0，去掉这些
And instead make dw a vector.
而是定义dw为一个向量
So I'm going to set dw = np.zeros and
设置dw = np.zeros((n(x),1))
let's make this an x but
one dimensional vector.
定义了一个x行，1维的向量
Then here instead of this full loop
over the individual components,
从而替代了循环每个组成
we just use this vector value operation.
我们仅仅使用了一个向量操作
dw += x(i)
times（乘以） dz(i).
And then finally and so that this
最后
we will just have dw div = m.
我们得到dw = dw/m
So now we've gone from having two for
loops to just one for loop.
现在我们通过将两层循环转成一层循环
We still have this one for loop that loops
over the individual training examples.
我们仍然还有这个循环训练样本
So I hope this video gave you
a sense of vectorization.
希望这个视频给了你一点向量化感觉
And by getting rid of one for loop,
your code will already run faster.
减少一层循环使你代码更快
But it turns out we could do even better,
so the next video,
但事实证明我们能做得更好 所以在下个视频
we'll talk about how to vectorize
logistic regression even further, and
进一步的讲解逻辑回归
you see a pretty surprising result.
得到更好的监督结果
That, without using any for loops, without
needing a for loop over the training
到此，通过在训练中没有任何循环
examples, you could write code to
process the entire training set.
写出代码去运行整个训练集
So pretty much all at the same time.
到此为止一切都好
So let's see that in the next video.
让我们看下一个视频